<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>But does she know so?</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on But does she know so?</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Credit where credit is due - theme made by [sharadcodes](https://github.com/sharadcodes/hugo-theme-serial-programmer)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wisdoms from building a patio</title>
      <link>/2024/06/30/building-a-patio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/2024/06/30/building-a-patio/</guid>
      <description>We built our own patio. Applause. The sin of not having a DIY dad on either my or my partner&amp;rsquo;s side meant we accrued many mistakes. Even Google couldn&amp;rsquo;t prepare us. If you&amp;rsquo;re one of those people who&amp;rsquo;d like to ask me &amp;ldquo;what advice do you have?&amp;rdquo;, here&amp;rsquo;s my letter to you:
Lesson 1: FOR THE LOVE OF GOD, ASK YOUR TILE SUPPLIER THE WEIGHT OF YOUR TILES We were advised to stay away from laying porcelain or ceramic tiles (very sound advice indeed), because they&amp;rsquo;re expensive and are more prone to cracking if you make mistakes elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI will not save your business</title>
      <link>/drafts/ai-will-not-save-your-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/drafts/ai-will-not-save-your-business/</guid>
      <description>Businesses laying off seems to be tied to AI (see Discord post on 11/01/2024 on #tech-support) This is a flawed assumption Many businesses laying off to help with profitability So do you really believe that cutting down on AI will reduce your expenditure that much?  Some businesses have a large chunk of its revenue in ads Many businesses don&amp;rsquo;t want to admit this is a problem Relying on ads is a quick way to make money in lieu of a differentiating revenue stream Your business is then in the business of advertising - you&amp;rsquo;re not a tech company, you&amp;rsquo;re a marketing company So why is this so common?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Cassandra performs faster writes at high throughput</title>
      <link>/drafts/why-cassandra-performs-faster-writes-at-high-throughput/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/drafts/why-cassandra-performs-faster-writes-at-high-throughput/</guid>
      <description>This paper from 2017 suggests that Cassandra is faster at writes at high throughput, and even outperforms Redis at the 0.1m to 1m writes scale. Why is that? How come Redis gets faster after 1m writes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I develop efficiently</title>
      <link>/drafts/how-i-develop-efficiently/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/drafts/how-i-develop-efficiently/</guid>
      <description> Using cookiecutter templates Using custom builders in Github workflows Think about all the -ility&amp;rsquo;s of your architecutre (see source)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrapping with OpenAPI</title>
      <link>/drafts/bootstrapping-with-openapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/drafts/bootstrapping-with-openapi/</guid>
      <description>Something about how difficult it is to bootstrap, including with oapi-codegen, despite the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to make it easier.
Use this to start a series about rating tooling with:
 How easy it is to learn Whether it&amp;rsquo;s good for personal projects, small teams or enterprises Cost of running  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brag because it helps others</title>
      <link>/2022/07/05/brag-because-it-helps-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/2022/07/05/brag-because-it-helps-others/</guid>
      <description>Something that&amp;rsquo;s always plagued my career is my silence about my achievements.
Despite being a loud and outgoing person in my personal life, sometimes to the point of being a show off, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t translate to my professional life. I never quite knew what was worth bragging about to get me recognised.
Many of you may recognise this behaviour. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to brag about your work, maybe for one of the following reasons:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast refreshing files on Windows when running React on WSL</title>
      <link>/drafts/fast-refreshing-files-windows-on-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/drafts/fast-refreshing-files-windows-on-wsl/</guid>
      <description>I ran into some trouble where React fast refresh stopped working when I ran a devcontainer on Windows. If I mounted my devcontainer on a Windows file path, fast refresh stopped working; however, if I mounted the devcontainer on a path in WSL 2, React fast refresh did work.
First of all, running a devcontainer on the Windows filesystem with WSL 2 negatively impacts performance. Running the React development server in the devcontainer when mounted to a WSL 2 path was so much faster than on Windows (a few seconds vs 2 mins) - so there is at least that benefit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Diversity Paradox</title>
      <link>/drafts/the-diversity-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/drafts/the-diversity-paradox/</guid>
      <description>Write something about how people who are minorities get asked to do glue work because they&amp;rsquo;re the only ones with insight into hiring minorities; but this means that they do not focus enough on engineering.
Similarly, in economic crises, diversity driven events are the first to be sacrificed and minorities (or women) are the first to suffer (explain why).
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The difference between operational transformations (OTs) and CRDTs</title>
      <link>/2022/05/09/the-difference-between-ots-and-crdts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/2022/05/09/the-difference-between-ots-and-crdts/</guid>
      <description>How do you ensure systems remain consistent even when a partial network failure happens between them? Seems impossible, right?
A common approach would delegate a leader in a system, whereby all nodes would send changess to the leader first. The leader is then responsible for propogating the changes to all replicas. This approach is simple but can be slow, since the messages have to traverse a network. In the event of a network partition, your system may end up with a split brain with inconsistent data across the partition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Lucene performs searches over word conjunctions</title>
      <link>/2022/05/08/lucene-conjunction-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/2022/05/08/lucene-conjunction-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Apache Lucene is an open source search software used by many tech giants, including Twitter and LinkedIn to power their sites&#39; search features. It offers the ability to search for multiple words across multiple documents, otherwise known as a conjunction. How is Lucene able to quicklyperform these conjunctions?This is where the leapfrog algorithm comes in. The leapfrog algorithm is used to find word conjunctions across several documents. Before we dive into how this algorithm works, we should explain a few things first:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
