<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on But does she know so?</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on But does she know so?</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Credit where credit is due - theme made by [sharadcodes](https://github.com/sharadcodes/hugo-theme-serial-programmer)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How NTP servers work</title>
      <link>/2022/02/20/how-ntp-servers-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/2022/02/20/how-ntp-servers-work/</guid>
      <description>She still doesn&amp;rsquo;t know. Questions  How are corrections made to a local block? How is it possible that NTP doesn&amp;rsquo;t skew the clock further when it makes the adjustment?  Notes References  A really detailed write up of NTP servers that I should condense  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to learn through digital media</title>
      <link>/2022/02/20/how-to-learn-through-digital-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/2022/02/20/how-to-learn-through-digital-media/</guid>
      <description>She still doesn&amp;rsquo;t know. Questions Notes  Because of the fact that digital media doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it easy to write in the margins, or create references to other material, it becomes hard to read syntopically through web articles or e-books. Mention tools/techniques that could help achieve syntopic reading through digital media People can learn through more than just reading via digital media, so how can that be factored into learning?  References </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The difference between a CNAME and ALIAS record</title>
      <link>/2022/02/01/difference-between-cname-and-alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/2022/02/01/difference-between-cname-and-alias/</guid>
      <description>She still doesn&amp;rsquo;t know. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The difference between login, non-login, interactive and non-interactive shells</title>
      <link>/2022/02/01/difference-between-shell-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/2022/02/01/difference-between-shell-types/</guid>
      <description>She still doesn&amp;rsquo;t know. Questions  How is this distinguished by the OS? Is there a way for me to tell if I&amp;rsquo;m in a login/non-login interactive shell from my session? How do you tell the difference between an interactive/non-interactive shell? You can by checking for the existence of a prompt env var $PS1 Can you distinguish between an interactive/non-interactive shell in the same way across all Linux distros? When do the profile/rc files run with respective to each combination of login/non-login interactive/non-interactive shells?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How network interfaces work</title>
      <link>/2022/01/26/how-network-interfaces-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sanyia.saidova@gmail.com (Sanyia Saidova)</author>
      <guid>/2022/01/26/how-network-interfaces-work/</guid>
      <description>She still doesn&amp;rsquo;t know. Questions  What exactly are they? Are they a hardware device or can it be virtualised? If it&amp;rsquo;s virtualised, how can I create my own? How do network sockets relate to a network interface? Is the stuff that I wrote in the 20211228 time note correct?  Notes  On the 20211228 time note, I wrote some initial notes about them  References  Really good ELI5 explanation of a network socket Quora explanation  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
